RESUME: JOZEF LACKO (English)



Profile

I am a full stack software engineer with 6+ years work experience strongly concentrated on building Web applications using JavaScript, TypeScript and Java.
Currently I work more on the front-end!

Full name Jozef Lacko Address Vienna, Austria Year of birth 1989 Citizenship Slovakia (EU) Marital status married

Email jlacko27@gmail.com Phone +436603279298

Skills

Mainly Front-end: JavaScript, TypeScript, NodeJS, Npm, React, Css and Html.

Backend: Java, Spring, Maven

Technologies & Tools: Docker, Jenkins, Jira and Confluence, IntelliJ IDEA

I believe that I have a good sense for design, details and presentation skills.

Languages

Slovak Native English Advanced German Advanced

Other

I consider myself as a very honest and happy person who believes that motivation can be more valuable than experience.

Education

Master of Engineering in Business Informatics
 September 2013 - May 2015

Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Informatics, Technical University of Kosice, Slovakia

• Bachelor of Engineering in Business Informatics

September 2010 - June 2013

Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Informatics, Technical University of Kosice, Slovakia

Work Experience

 Web Software Engineer at Austrian lotteries GmbH, Full-time, Vienna, Austria January 2019 - Present

I work at Austrian Lotteries as a Full-stack developer in a team of 9 people. My main role is to design and build web-front-end of company internal tools with the latest tech-stack. I define concepts and apis for layouting, validation, testing and maintenance.

Technologies & Tools: NodeJs, Npm, Lerna, TypeScript, JavaScript, React, Material-UI, Jest, React Testing Library, Cypress, Java, Maven, Spring, Rest API, OpenApi, Oracle SQL, Git, Mercurial, Subversion, Jenkins, Docker, OpenShift, Jira, Confluence, Scrum

 Web Software Engineer at Workflow EDV GmbH, Full-time, Vienna, Austria June 2015 - December 2018

<u>I was the major Frontend developer</u> of the enterprise web application, focusing mostly on time, travel and personnel management. My main responsibilities were the development of the responsive skin of our progressive web app and significantly improving the user experience. Product contained 350+ UIs which needed a lot of analytical and design skills. In the company I started as a full-time trainee and switched to a regular contract after 10 months. <u>The Company won "Technology Excellence Award 2019" for innovative technology and solution quality in the categories of functional scope, usability and intuitive handling.</u>

Technologies & Tools: NodeJs, Npm, Lerna, Typescript, JavaScript, React, Jquery, Bootstrap, Xslt, Xml, BPMN Workflows, Jest, Java, Maven, Spring, Rest API, SQL, Subversion, Hudson, Jira, Confluence, Scrum

 Software Engineer - Internship at University of Tokyo, Full-time, Japan September 2014 - October 2014

With the help of the IAESTE exchange program, I was accepted for a 10 weeks internship at the University of Tokyo in Japan. Internship was aimed at the effectiveness of parallel computation with Fortran programming language. It was my first experience abroad and a great opportunity to experience other cultures, for which I am absolutely thankful.

Technologies & Tools: Fortran, C

 Web Software Engineer at Technical University of Kosice, Contract, Slovakia July 2014 - May 2015

<u>I have been selected from among more than 200 students to work on the university projects.</u> Our client was one of the subsidiaries of the United States Steel Corporation placed in Slovakia. In a team of 7 people, we implemented enterprise web applications responsible for managing production of an iron ore. My main responsibility was Frontend development.

Technologies & Tools: C#, ASP.NET Razor, JavaScript, Jquery

In the past, I also worked as a web tester and internet service technician.

LEBENSLAUF: JOZEF LACKO (Deutsch)



Profil

Ich bin ein Full-Stack Softwareentwickler mit 6+ Jahren Berufserfahrung, die sich stark auf das Erstellen von Webapplikationen mit JavaScript, TypeScript und Java konzentriert.

Name Jozef Lacko Adresse Wien, Österreich Geburtsjahr 1989 Staatsbürgerschaft Slowakei (EU) Beziehungsstatus Verheiratet Email jlacko27@gmail.com Telefon +436603279298

Kompetenzen

Hauptsächlich Frontend: JavaScript, TypeScript, NodeJS, Npm, React, Css und Html.

Backend: Java, Spring, Maven

Technologien & Tools: Docker, Jenkins, Jira und Confluence, IntelliJ IDEA

Ich glaube, dass ich ein gutes Gespür für Design, Details und Präsentationsfähigkeiten habe.

Sprachen

Slowakisch Muttersprache **Englisch** sehr gute Kenntnisse **Deutsch** sehr gute Kenntnisse

Andere

Ich betrachte mich als eine sehr ehrliche und glückliche Person, die glaubt, dass Motivation wertvoller sein kann als Erfahrung. Ich liebe es, über das Leben zu sprechen und suche immer nach positiven Menschen. In meiner Freizeit entwickle ich mit meinen Freunden kleine Projekte.

Bildung

Master of Engineering in Wirtschaftsinformatik
 September 2013 - Mai 2015
 Fakultät für Elektrotechnik und Informatik, Technische Universität Kosice, Slowakei

Bachelor of Engineering in Wirtschaftsinformatik
 September 2010 - Juni 2013
 Fakultät für Elektrotechnik und Informatik, Technische Universität Kosice, Slowakei

Arbeitserfahrung

 Web-Entwickler bei den Österreichischen Lotterien GmbH, Vollzeit, Wien, Österreich Januar 2019 - Heute

Ich arbeite bei Österreichische Lotterien als Full-Stack-Entwickler in einem Team von neun Personen. <u>Meine Hauptaufgabe ist unternehmensinterne Tools mit den neuesten Tech-Stack zu bauen</u> (Nodejs, TypeScript, React, Cypress). <u>Ich definiere Konzepte und APIs für Layout, Validierung, Test und Wartung.</u>

Technologien & Tools: NodeJs, Npm, Lerna, TypeScript, JavaScript, React, Material-Ul, Jest, React Testing Library, Cypress, Java, Maven, Spring Boot,Oracle SQL, Git, Mercurial, Subversion, Jenkins, Docker, OpenShift, Jira, Confluence, Scrum

 Web-Entwickler bei Workflow EDV GmbH, Vollzeit, Wien, Österreich Juni 2015 - Dezember 2018

Ich war der führende Frontend-Entwickler der Enterprise-Webanwendung und konzentrierte mich ebenfalls auf Zeit-, Reise- und Personalmanagement. Ich habe mit Technologien wie JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Xslt, XML, Java, Spring, Maven und BPMN gearbeitet. Meine Hauptverantwortung war die Entwicklung des Responsive Skins unserer progressiven Web-App und die signifikante Verbesserung der Benutzererfahrung. Das Produkt enthielt mehr als 350 Uls.. In der Firma habe ich als Praktikant angefangen. Das Unternehmen wurde mit dem "Technology Excellence Award 2019" für innovative Technologie und Lösungsqualität in den Kategorien Funktionsumfang, Benutzerfreundlichkeit und intuitive Handhabung ausgezeichnet.

Technologien & Tools: NodeJs, Npm, Lerna, Typescript, JavaScript, React, Jquery, Bootstrap, Xslt, Xml, BPMN Workflows, Jest, Java, Maven, Spring, SQL, Subversion, Hudson, Jira, Confluence, Scrum

 Entwickler - Praktikum an der Universität von Tokio, Vollzeit, Japan September 2014 - Oktober 2014

Mit Hilfe des IAESTE-Austauschprogramms wurde ich für ein 10-wöchiges <u>Praktikum an der Universität Tokio in Japan</u> aufgenommen. Das Praktikum zielte auf die Effektivität der parallelen Berechnung mit der Programmiersprache Fortran ab. Es war <u>meine erste Auslandserfahrung</u> und eine großartige Gelegenheit, andere Kulturen kennenzulernen, für die ich absolut dankbar bin.

Technologien & Tools: Fortran, C

 Web-Entwickler an der Technischen Universität Kosice, Auf Vertrag, Slowakei Juli 2014 - Mai 2015

Ich wurde aus mehr als 200 Studenten ausgewählt, um an den Universitätsprojekten zu arbeiten. Unser Kunde war eine der Tochtergesellschaften der United States Steel Corporation in der Slowakei. In einem Team von sieben Mitarbeitern haben wir C# Webapp für Unternehmen implementiert, die für die Verwaltung der Produktion eines Eisenerzes verantwortlich sind. Meine Hauptverantwortung war die Frontend-Entwicklung.

Technologien & Tools: C#, ASP.NET Razor, JavaScript, Jquery

In der Vergangenheit habe ich auch als Webtester und Internet-Service-Techniker gearbeitet.